Today on my podcast, I sit down with
Nate Beagle. He's a voice actor,
puppeteer, and audio producer with over
25 years in the entertainment industry.
From working with Sesame Street and the
Jim Henson Company to voicing characters
in national campaigns for Xbox and Taco
Bell, Nate's career spans nearly every
corner of storytelling. I met him uh as
an announcer for an awards ceremony.
He's narrated over 30 audio books,
including works by bestselling authors
like James Patterson. He brings a rare
blend of technical skills and creative
soul to everything he touches. In this
episode, Nate opens up about the
philosophy behind performance, the
discipline of voice acting, and the art
to breathing life into characters. The
art of breathing life into characters.
It's packed with insight, encouragement,
and a good dose of humor. A conversation
that feels both masterclass and campfire
chat. Let's dive in.
Junkyard Love podcast. At what age do we
learn how to have better comprehensive
Junkyard Love podcast
I'm a big fan of greenery and nature. So
it's right now pretty plump and green.
So I'm enjoying Austin at the moment.
Plump and green is how I like my That's
how I prefer my nature, actually. Yeah,
I I prefer it to be plump and green.
I've actually been contemplating naming
my first two children plump and green.
So, plump and green.
[Music]
Wait, wait for it. Wait for it.
Dude, I was actually going to I was
hoping that you would bring the sound
effects. I was listening to you on
another podcast and you were Oh, I go
Well, I mean, welcome. Um, we do have a
live audience here. No Zoom is left
unsoundffected
by me. Yeah. Do you get off Do you often
get podcast guests that bring their own
sound effects? No. First timer, baby. I
like I like to break new ground. I like
to break new ground here.
That's funny. Which podcast were you
listening to? I'm curious. Uh with uh
the
uh the host's name was Bob.
I forget the name. Oh, uh DJ Bob. DJ
Bob. Yeah, that was one podcast. He has
been a super good friend of mine. Talk
about somebody breaking ground. Um,
buddy of mine. He's I call him a like
sweet baby kid. He was a kid when I
first met him. He was 15 when I met him.
And uh he's almost 30 now. So I've known
him for a good chunk of time. And um
young kid I guess he'll always be it's
you know how you know I feel like that
way with my my nephew is now 15. He's
twice the size of me. But I always like,
you know, they're always just like
encased in amber in Jurassic Park style.
Like you're always this size and this
age in my mind when I think you're also
still cradling them also, right? Um so
but Bob DJ Bob um the DJ Bob show please
everyone look it up. It's he uh kid with
keep saying kid. He's a a young
gentleman with he's got cerebal palsy
and he's his um passion is you know and
his level of CP he doesn't wasn't able
especially as a kid to get out a lot do
a lot of stuff so he really embraced
popular culture and animation and and
television and music and that became his
life really and so and his goal he
always wanted to be a DJ a radio DJ
and
you know kind of created his own show
and his own podcast and his he's been
doing the DJ Bob show in various forms
and now it's pretty much on like weekly
kind of podcast uh for like 15 years um
as a kid with CP. Yeah. Wow. And he's
he's awesome. So I got to know him
through and I'm sure we'll get into it
through you know part of his pop culture
fascination was puppetry, Sesame Street,
Muppets and stuff like that. And that's
how we got connected um on the the the
earlier days of the social medias and
the in the in the early days of
podcasting. Um I had a I had a puppetry
podcast back in the day. Um that uh is
how we kind of got in contact and yeah
stayed in contact ever since and I've
done a lot of audio stuff and voice over
for his show and I was a audio a
producer for his show for a good number
of years. Um, and then you know, work
life and work a lot, so I wasn't able to
dedicate as much time to it as I want
to, but he's got other people helping
him out. But super good, dude. I love
that you listened to that chat. It was a
fun It was a fun chat. I always have a
good time talking with him. Yeah. Yeah,
it was enjoyable. I always like the
perspective of like uh longtime work
friends. Let's sit down and kind of like
break that fourth wall of uh like, "Hey,
I did this thing for you and you did
this thing for me and we've been through
a lot together." And it's uh it's cool
to to put a microphone in front of that
relationship. I also from from I don't
know a ton about him, but just from what
you've said and listening to that
episode, um I dude I admire someone who
just like they just see something that
they want to do and they don't wait for
someone to give them a way to do it.
They're just like, I'm going to make
this happen. I I feel like so many
creatives can relate to that. It's like
if you see something that's not
available where where you're at, then
make it, you know, like just make a door
if there's not one. I love that. He is
the personification of that of passion.
Passion taking over and not letting
something not letting anybody tell you
you can't do it. And he of course has
had a lot of people tell him he can't do
something because of his physical
limitations. And it's a really it's it
was a in in working and knowing with
knowing him for as long as I have and
getting a chance to even talk in that
way of just like just let's just talk to
even though I knew it it's it's so
I don't know it makes you makes your
heart grow three sizes that day you know
when you see you know everyone has their
own trials and tribulations and everyone
has their own hang-ups their own walls
that they need to climb or break through
in order to to do what they need to do.
But seeing, you know, getting a
different perspective of somebody who
has going through something that not a
lot of people can relate to
um and his challenges of life and health
challenges and physical limitations and
uh you know
persevering through that and making his
own way and doing it how he's able to do
it, figuring out a way to do it and
riding that passion wave, you know what
I mean? and like cuz he has he's had a
lot of people say, "You can't do this.
You can't be a radio disc jockey." He's
had people boldly and rudely say
horrible things to him um in regards to
what they believed he could or could not
do in this realm of and so yeah, it's
pretty it's awesome. He's inspired. He
inspires me all the time for sure. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. I I definitely picked that
up from the episode. I'm inspired by him
as well. I I love that, man. If someone
tells you you can't do something, a lot
of times you figure out who the heck you
are on the other side of just action
through those things other people tell
you you can't do or or other things that
just don't really have a route and you
just just find a way to make it happen.
And then suddenly you look back and it's
been 15 years and you're like, "Whoa,
I've been doing that thing that like
nobody thought I could do." That's
pretty cool. As the great Dr. Ian
Malcolm once said, "Life uh uh finds a
way."
Indeed. Bravo. Uh, okay. All right, Mr.
Nate.
Valiant. Uh, Mr. Nate, welcome. Welcome
to welcome to the Junkyard Love podcast.
Thank you so much for agreeing to do
this, man. I appreciate your time. Um,
Jacob, this is awesome. I can't wait.
I'm so stoked and I am so stoked that
you know how we got in I was say how we
got engaged, how we engaged, how we
connected, how we met and bringing us to
this kind of point. It's awesome. Yeah,
let's talk at all. Let's let's let
everybody know. Do you think if we were
engaged, would you be the proposer or
would I be the proposer? Oh, I would I
don't know. We'd probably propose at the
same time. Okay. How would you do it? I
I think we would do it at the same time,
but I would we would try to outdo each
other in in creating production for
sure. Yep. We would try to out Yeah. in
our levels in our in our histories of in
the entertainment business and doing
fullcale stage productions and things
like that we would try to uh outdo I
would probably get well one if we were
engaged I would know like your favorite
like cartoon character your ver your
favorite actor your favorite cartoon
your favorite animation I'm going to ask
you about it later and then I would
either get a cameo I would have I would
go to Cameo and I would get this guy to
propose to you on behalf of me in the
voice of like your animated icon. Yes,
the answer is yes. That's what I would
do. The answer is yes. So, we're engag
legally, I think. I mean, this is
recorded, so we might we might legally
be engaged. It's happened. It's happened
now. We'll uh I'll have my lawyer look
it over. No, but I love that how we
connected and we we we you and I just
kind of jived and bonded right away,
even just working on a show together.
And uh I love that it kind of just
stemmed from this just like hey let's
stay in touch.
So I'm happy to be here. I was actually
I was sitting next to a friend the
videographer. So the show we were just
doing I was the director for and you
were the announcer for uh we have we
have actually crossed paths before but
I'm typically in a different role so I'm
very much like uh DJ with his headphones
on over in the corner like I'm not very
uh uh as extroverted as I get to be when
I am in technical director director.
last show we got to actually like
interact more, right? Yeah. And so, um,
yeah, it's it's nice to meet people like
that and and I always this podcast kind
of, you know, that old saying of, uh, as
you walk the path appears or like as you
walk the bricks lay themselves or
whatever it is. Um, roads where we're
going, we don't need roads. Precisely.
And that's how this podcast works, dude.
is I I was sitting next to the
videographer uh as we were at the
airport and I was messaging you on
LinkedIn and it was just this perfect
like as I was talking about it we're
like yeah yeah we should definitely have
you on uh let's have this talk. So it
just it worked out well because we we
connected on LinkedIn and then when I
looked at your page the the most your
most recent post was a clip from your
podcast. I was like oh right on let me
check out what his podcast is and it
just it was serendipitous. it just jived
because um you know and then I did my
little not even like a hard self. I was
like I would hey I'd happy to come on
and chat. I love doing podcasts in
addition to this you know with the theme
of your podcast. Um I was like yeah I'm
an unorthodox teacher in in addition to
uh a talent performer producer audio guy
like you as well. Um, I I I teach not
not I literally I ended a half an hour
before we hopped on here. I changed my
shirt really quick because I was soaking
wet sweating, but I did a whole uh VO
character workshop for a group of um you
know 9 to 13 year olds uh that are
professional kids that audition and
stuff like that. So, we had a whole
group um character VO animation workshop
just just before uh you and I hopped on.
Okay. Well, I want to hear all about
that. Can you give me the details on
that? And while you're at it, uh, I'm
just barreling through on you. Give me
your bio if if if you will, if you'll
give me like your quick elevator pitch
and then tell me about what you did
today. Elevator pitch. So, what I say
when I introduce myself to people in
this in this capacity or in any kind of
capacity, I say, "Hey guys, I'm Nate
Beagle. I'm a voice actor and I'm a
puppeteer. And what I do for a living is
I bring characters and stories to life."
And that's that is my that I leave it at
that. And then it we can go we can go
deep, right? It can get deep. That's
like a That seems like a simple phrase,
but man, it gets deep. There's a lot of
facets to that, a lot of elements to
that. And I'm sure we'll talk a little
bit about my history and what, you know,
what what has brought me to this point
in this wacky life of that we lead. Um,
but yeah, that's that's that's my quick
and short pitch. Voice actor, puppeteer,
I bring characters to life. And in I
have been doing this professionally
full-time for over 25 years. And I
through that time, through that journey
and my journey that still continues on,
I have very gratefully and thankfully
been able to uh do that storytelling,
bringing characters to life in many
different mediums
um on stage, on camera, um in voice
over, as a puppet, as a fleshy meatsack
puppet of myself. Um which is what I
don't prefer. I say what I like to do.
Nate, I prefer I um you see it on my
LinkedIn. They're like, "Hey, where's
Nate?" And you go, "Oh, he's behind the
mic or below the frame. That's where I
like to live. That's where I like to
hence our first thing. I love being the
announcer. I like being the guy behind
the curtain." Yeah. Yeah. It's funny. I
I have a DJ background and I I much
prefer to go back to the time where the
DJ was hidden. I want to do more events
where people are like, "Who is the DJ
and and where is he?" And like you never
get to see him. I want to play more like
that. It's that like the it's It's the
Wizard of Oz. Yeah. Right. It's the man
behind the curtain. Yeah. Kind of vibe.
And it's um Yeah. Now DJs DJs are front
and center now. It's a big thing. Yeah.
Right. They love it.
Look, man. When I when I was 22, 23, I
love that attention, too. Now it's like,
hey, put put some like put some
sanctioning around me in front of house
or something cuz I'm I'm jamming and I
want to be jamming, but like it's not
about me. It's about the environment
we're creating, you know? Yeah. And I
think that's part of me too. It's like
and I've done, you know, when I uh was
pursuing a career in the arts, in the
performing arts, um it all starts with
like look at me, look at me, look at me
doing the thing. Yeah. Let me juggle.
Dance monkey dance kind of thing. Doing
stuff on stage as an actor, you know,
speech and drama in school, doing all
the musicals, all the plays. And um but
the through line for me uh was puppetry.
Puppetry is my was my gateway my gateway
drug into the into the entertainment
world. Um my uh I say I call it my light
switch moment. Um Jacob um I don't I'm
not sure what our age difference is. So,
we should probably know this before we
got engaged, but um I am a child of the
1980s
and um when I was uh but a young lad in
the 80s, there was a show called Fraggle
Rock. Sure. You're probably familiar
with Frag. You're pro. Are you familiar
with Fraggle Rock? I I know the name. It
sparks a bell. Most definitely. Okay.
So, but you know Sesame Street? Yes. You
know the Muppets? Yes. Kermit, Fuzzy,
Piggy, all that. Right. So, I grew up I
was a kid that grew up watching Sesame
Street as many kids over the last 50
years were kids raised on Sesame Street,
right? Watching these characters,
learning from these characters, loving
these characters, laughing with these
characters, right? And it was at age
seven in the mid80s, I had my light
switch moment had watching a show that
Jim Henson ended up doing called The
Fraggle Rock. Um, it was a show that he
put together in the 80s and it was like
his way of it was his desire to like I
want to solve world peace. Basically, he
created the show to like bridge cultural
gaps and it became a global phenomenon.
They ended up being like talk about like
franchises, you know, how The Office has
like
there's an off version of the show The
Office in like every country. Yeah.
Fraggle Rock had that. There was a
Fraggle Rock and the same thing Sesame
Street has that. There's a Sesame Street
in like multiple countries. Um like
their their version of it and Fraggle
Rock was that it was like creating the
Fraggles lived in this world and hidden
from the real world of us humans and
they called us referred to us as the
silly creatures and and then there was
another world of other creatures called
gorgs and stuff like that. So they were
like this bridge in between these two
worlds and fascinating really fun. You
can look it up. a new version of it on
Apple TV Plus. Um, basically conceived
and done uh by the great John Tartagia,
who is one of my Is Duncan Trussell in
that? Am I thinking of the wrong one?
The Do you know who Duncan is? Yeah.
Yeah. Yes. Yes. Ah, okay. I've watched a
couple episodes of that. I'm a big
Duncan Trussell fan, so I've I've
stumbled across that one. Duncan
Trussell was uh Doc, I believe.
Is that right, Duncan? I've watched it.
My memory with things like the specifics
on shows is horrible some days. Yes. I
believe we're thinking of the same
person. The the actor, the older actor,
Duncan Trussell. Is that right? He has
like a a very scratchy voice. Very um
original voice. Yeah. Yeah. Who's in
Boondock Saints? I don't know. Is that
the actor we're talking about? I think
we're thinking of the same person. I'm
trying now. I'm like someone in the
comments are listening is screaming that
person. If only we had a way to look
this up while we're literally talking to
each other. Jamie. Jamie, look it up.
Um, but uh, watching Fraggle Rock, I had
the light switch moment. I was 7 years
old and I went from knowing these
characters, loving these characters to
going, "How do they do that?" Like, I
had already grasp the concept at this
point that was like, I get it. They're
not real, right? I get, spoilers. Sorry
everyone listening.
The Muppets and the puppets ancestry,
they're not real. Um, there are I get
that there are human beings
bringing those characters to life.
There's somebody doing that.
How are they doing that? I got to know.
And that was the light switch moment.
And so where some people might be like,
"Oh gosh, my whole life is a lie. The
magic is ruined." Um, I was the magic
exploded even more. I needed to know
what was going on below that frame. how
are those performers bringing these
characters to life? And then not too
long after that, there was a um and you
could probably find this on YouTube.
It's pretty great. The Jim Henson was
very open with showing the magic behind
the magic. He was very much he pulled
what's behind the curtain, right? It
whereas like some other companies,
Disney a lot of the times doesn't like
to don't say you don't need to know
what's happening, right? Don't ruin the
magic. for Jim it was like no no no the
magic is what's happening down here and
bringing this to life this is where the
magic is and people need to see that and
so there was a show that he did it's
called the Jim Henson Hour um that was
later on either late 80s or early 90s
that came on and there's a phenomen
fantastic I think one of the last
episodes of the Jim Henson Hour all the
Muppets uh uh like there's this whole
bit of like Gonzo they're showing like
how they have to do like the visual
tricks like Gonzo's gonna enter the
frame and pick up a phone, but Gonzo
doesn't have live hands. He's not a live
hand puppet. He's a what's called a hand
and rod puppet. And his hands are little
floppy kind of fingers. And so they
literally walk you through like Gonzo
enters the frame, the phone's ringing,
he walks over to the frame, he reaches
up and then they have to cut and they
cut to a shot where now they have
attached the phone to the puppet's hand
and it's like a closeup shot and now
he's like, "Oh, hello. You don't say."
Does the whole joke like, "You don't
say. You don't say." And then and then
hang it up. Cut to again. Now it's that
wide shot where he removes the hand and
now he's not holding on to it. And that
whole little simple bit, right? Cuz it
was like with puppetry, we c he can't
actually go up there and grab the phone.
So, we have to do this cut visual
effect, if you will, some, you know,
movie magic. And he broke it down. Broke
it down into that whole thing. And so
that was really fascinating and like
just like, oh, that's so cool. It's so
cool how but like how quick that is. And
we watch it and go, oh yeah, it's
totally by mine that he just picks it
up, but not even thinking, oh, he can't
actually physically do it. So that's why
they had to do a cut. It just all
seamlessly works and blends together in
the storytelling aspect of it and you
write along with it. And so it was
really cool to see the behind the scenes
of that cut to the end of that episode.
I believe it's that same episode. It's
all the muppets, all the characters
together in the shot and then the camera
starts to back they they they even make
a bit of they're like ah who's who are
these people? Like down here they're
like ah who are these people? And the
camera pans out slowly and you see then
you get to see everybody, all the
puppeteers holding the characters,
looking down at the monitors and still
staying in character, keeping those
characters alive. And I was just that I
need to do that. Kind of like we were
talking about DJ Bob of like like he's
like I'm the I'm going to do this and I
was like I need that. That's what I
need. I need to do that. And that's what
started my journey really and I say this
I was just doing a workshop with kids I
do a lot of workshops with kids in
voiceover and uh I say when I'm giving
them my little history I was like you
know kids back in my day we didn't have
a thing called the Googles or the
YouTubes or the zooms we had to if I
needed to learn something I had to go to
this place this magical place called the
library and in this place there were
these things called books on the walls
and so you know I play that little bit
up but I have to go I had to go to the
library check out every book that I
could in school at the public library
about puppetry the art of puppetry and
the more I immersed myself in that
knowledge of like just the the history
of it you know puppetry is one of the
oldest forms of storytelling that we as
human beings have with each other like
just after like painting on cave walls
is puppetry, taking things and
manipulating them, showing like, oh,
this big thing chased me, you know what
I mean? Bridging language barriers and
stuff like that. I was just the more I
learned about it, the more I was like,
this is amazing. And through that
process of learning my the history of
puppetry, the art of puppetry, learning
how to build my own puppet, how to like
from scratch, how to, you know, sew, how
to, you know, design and, you know, make
patterns and all of this kind of stuff.
And just from book after book after book
through that process I discovered where
I was really gravitating towards was the
performance aspect of it was once this
character is
is is here physically
now physically animating it bringing
life to this inanimate object. Right?
That's where that's where I noticed that
was like this is my thing. This is where
I'm this is my strength in this. this is
what's really propelling me through
this. Um, and it was through that whole
process of like designing a character
from scratch and then physically
building it and then physically
animating it and then of course that cut
to giving it a voice and all that kind
of stuff. Giving it thought, giving it
feeling, giving it personality, giving
it movement and and breathing life into
this inanimate sack of fur with
eyeballs, right? You know what I mean?
Yeah. And it was through that. And so
that was my passion. I was like, I want
to be a professional puppeteer. I want
to be those guys. And it was like, I
have two goals for myself. I want to
work on Sesame Street and I want to be
uh work with the Jim Henson company,
work with the Muppets. And I've since
gotten to do both of those things
multiple times. And it was through that
journey, and that was my laser focus was
puppetry. Now, where I was growing up,
there wasn't really a puppetry outlet
for me. It's not like it is today where
I could click on a YouTube video and
learn how to do monitor work on
puppetry.
And there wasn't a lot of
people teaching puppets in my where I
was growing up. I was grow uh I was
going to grade school and and high
school in the central Florida area and
there wasn't a lot going on. There was
some puppet stuff within school. There
was this company
um that's I believe is still around. I
was talking about it on the DJ Bob show
actually. Um it was called Kids on the
Block. Are you familiar with Kids on the
Block? It's been around for like 30 plus
years.
And it basically was um puppet shows
designed for like middle school kids to
be the puppeteers and go tour around
elementary schools to teach other kids
about kids with disabilities. Oh. And so
these were puppet characters that all
had a specific disability. Like there
was a blind puppet, there was a puppet
with CP, uh there was even um like a a
puppet care kid that had been in a
houseire like a burn victim and like
very similar like Sesame Streetesque
things of like, hey, this kid is
different. Sure. Yeah. And it's okay and
he can still be your friend. It was it
was very much in that vein, right? It
was pretty cool. That was a puppetry
outlet that I did have and I I was a
part of that. the kids on the block. Um,
not the new kids on the block. They were
just the kids on the block. I wasn't
Donnie Wahlberg. Um, but um, so that was
an outlet. So I had to go through
because like I said, the core element of
it for me was the performance aspect of
it, bringing things to life. I went
through the traditional acting route and
I studied classical acting, acting 101.
I did all the speech and drama classes
in grade school. cut to high school
doing all the plays and then I found my
love of musicals, musical theater and
telling stories in that way and so doing
stuff as a human being but also
harnessing my acting skills as a
performer and whenever I could I would
input
what I was learning into my puppetry or
I would incorporate puppetry elements in
projects or in scenes or in sketches or
in plays or something like that if it
made sense. you know, at the time like
the only puppet thing that was really
kind of out there was like Little Shop
of Horrors was a puppet thing. This is
long before Avenue Q was a thing. Um,
so that was my thing. I cut to I as I'm
graduating college, I double major in
college in musical theater and you'll
appreciate this, my friend, digital
media production. Mhm. In the early
arts. I graduated high school in the
1900s.
Um, and I graduated college in 2003. And
from 99 to 2003, it was like, hey, this
new thing called digital media, this
this new thing called the internet, it
might take off, right? Um, and so I was
really fascinated with audio
storytelling always. And so in college
in that double major, performing as a
musical theater, but also doing digital
media production with a focus on
television and radio. Mhm. So I interned
at radio stations, interned in the news
vans, the local news station and stuff
like that, learning how to put together
stories and edit and all that kind of
stuff. Um, so that's what I did. Cut to
graduating
2003, sold my car, sold a majority of my
possessions,
and I
backpack and a suitcase and took the
Amtrak train to New York City. And I
said, I gave myself six months. So, I'm
gonna give myself six months to book
something. I saved up enough money at
this point to do that, including selling
a lot of my stuff. And I was like, six
months to book something. And uh I ended
up staying there for about 15 years. And
that's where I built up my career in
puppetry as a performer. Cut to now make
this incredibly long long- winded
spoilers. I talk for a living. Um but I
I think these little elements are like
important, right? They're all part of
this journey and one little element
leads to the next one which informs the
next one. And it was through my first
gig that I the first pro gig in New York
that I booked was uh a show called Die
Hard the Puppet Musical. Oh wow. And it
is just as awesome as it sounds. A
musical based on the movie Die Hard with
puppets. Okay. Okay. And it was just
amazing. Just incredible. And that's how
I got involved in the New York City
puppetry scene, working with the puppet
pros there that were that were there,
learning from them, connecting with them
very much. One show led to the next
show, which led to the next show, which
led to working with Jim Henson folk,
working on Sesame Street, working with
Jim Henson projects, working with those
professionals and the idols that I grew
up loving and watching. And talk about a
master class, just being in the room
with these performers and watching them
just effortlessly bring these characters
to life. And I'm just like just soaking
it all in. And one of my uh mentors, the
great Tyler Bunch, you guys can look up
Tyler Bunch. He's amazing. He's been
working with Sesame for oh well over 30
plus years and many different
characters, character performer, and a
voice actor. And he's the one that
literally, you know, I was so
hyperfocused. So, in spoilers, in New
York, I do a lot of kid shows, do a lot
of puppet stuff. I was doing all kinds
of stuff. Puppet stuff for kids, puppet
stuff for adults, puppet stuff, you
know, that that new fangled internet
thing was taking off. Doing stuff for
web series, you know, independent things
were it was cool because there was new
ways to like do stuff with puppet
characters. I was playing so many
different characters and working on
numerous projects with these colleagues
and and idols of mine. Tyler Bunch is
the guy that says to me,
"Did you ever think about doing voice
work?" I was like, "No,
no." I was so hyperfocused on pups. And
he's like, "You should you should think
about it. You should think about what
you're doing." I was like, "Really?" And
he's like, "Yeah, what you are doing?"
He saw and this is one of those to take
it into, you know, teaching and and and
having mentors and coaches and and
people that guide you, guides on your
journeys. It takes sometimes it takes
that one person to go,
yeah, this you see, maybe you should
look at this what you're doing.
And basically what he was saying, he
said, he was like, everything that you
are doing when you're playing a
character, he's like, I see it. I see
the the journey that you're going on
when playing your characters. Regardless
of how silly it is, regardless of how
little it was, I was putting the same
concerted effort into all of my
characters. And that was all that's
always been it's kind of been my root
thing. I go for it always. And I put a
lot of work into it. I regardless of how
small the the the bit part might have
been. I was always creating story
backstories, histories, you know, levels
of detail of their personalities and who
this character was in their world and
using that to fuel the characterization,
using that as the the as the as the the
the seed in which, you know, eventually
the voice would come out of. Nine times
out of 10, it was always, you know, a
fun voice or whatever that was doing to
for the character. But in doing so, I
was expanding my range vocally as well.
And I was able to really differentiate.
I was playing multiple characters in the
same show and making them all different.
That was always like a goal of mine. I
want to make sure that they were all
very unique and different. So they
didn't all sound the same, right? They
needed to. And how I got them to not
sound the same was like really
internally make them so inherently
different from each other. And then the
voice is what followed. And that was the
the the element that Tyler noticed and
he's like, "Yeah, the stuff that you're
doing will absolutely serve you
incredibly well in the voiceover world.
You think about that." And that's what
blew the door doors open for me. And I I
I
there's a lot more work in voiceover
than there is in puppetry. Yeah.
Spoilers. And I've been full-time VO and
with a little bit of puppetry whenever I
can ever since. And um yeah, that's so
that's a that's a little bit of a long a
long short story of how I've gotten and
through that through the voice over
diving into voiceover I've been able to
over the years 20 years now been able to
uh branch off into all the different
facets of voice over of course leading
into live announcing and stuff like that
that you and I met on doing like a live
award show and how that's one element
one genre of voiceover that I've been
able to uh get into and do and and do
pretty well. And um but yeah, my core
passion has always been puppetry, always
been character-driven, animation, video
games is primarily what I do. I do a lot
of dubbing. I have my own production
studio now. I do a lot of audio
post-production and things. I do a lot
of dubbing um for anime and other uh
foreign properties and stuff like that
because it's not just anime. Anime is
not the only foreign animation in town
um that want English voices on it. So
yeah, that's where and that's still
where my passion lives. But again, to
take it all the way back to the
beginning, I bring stories and
characters to life in whatever medium
that takes, but I put forth the same, it
all comes from the same place. And I
think because of that, all of my stuff
is worked, you know, and and having to
bend, I call it like bending the needle,
like you go down one path, but sometimes
you got to bend the needle a little bit
to make it fit through this one little
avenue,
but it all is rooted in the same kind of
place, if that makes sense. as I'm, you
know, doing. We're in ghost now and
we're making the pot. Yeah. With with
sees and to me more I'm feeling the
romance. Yeah. I mean, we are engaged,
Jacob. So, we are. Of course. Yeah.
We'll try to keep it PG on the podcast.
We don't want to PDA everybody out here.
Exactly. Man, so brilliant. I I really
love for one, I would like to ask what
that 6 months was like. For sure. I want
to know more about that six-month period
when you first moved to New York. But I
also just want to pinpoint before we go
there. Yeah. The power of encouragement.
Uh I had this I was writing some poetry
the other day about um uh
basically like human beings need
encouragement. Like I think it's it's
safe to say that it's an actual need.
Like if we don't have anybody around us
telling us or digging, you know, we
could we can make everything that we're
into so very muddy and just someone
could like see through the mud and go
like, "Hey, that thing you're really
good at it and I think it's awesome that
you do it." And then we're alone
afterwards an hour later going, "Huh?
I I I I love doing that thing and it's
helpful when people see it and I could
do that. It's pretty profound. So So the
encouragement um part is just so
profound and I love it and I love that
um so we we we inherently discount
ourselves. We're always talking
ourselves out of things, right? We're
why and why do we do that? Yeah. And
that's why it is it is it's some weird
subset
uh of of in our DNA why you know and not
everyone of course not everyone is like
this right but most of us tend to get
down on ourselves a lot right
it's a lot easier to go ah I can't do
that to like oh I could do this I should
do this it's hard and that might be part
of it right it's hard it's it's it's
it's hard to go after something that you
want um sometimes, right? And it and it
with the help of that encouragement um
is is yeah, it's paramount. It it is
it's massive. And that's that's
something that I absolutely apply to my
own coaching and my own teaching, my own
work with actors of all ages. And I
coach puppetry, I coach voiceover. Um
and I have actors of all ages. My
youngest is four and she's incredible.
Nice. Incredible. How fun. And my oldest
actor just turned 92. Equally as fun.
Equally as fun. And like you know it's
so and when the passion is shared and my
and that's what I do. I'm just always
encouraging everyone's journey
everyone's passion being able to
pinpoint this is where your strength is.
All right. Let's let's focus you know
because everyone learns something.
Everyone learns differently. Everyone's
journey is going to be different.
There's no one way. Bob, DJ Bob is a
great person to to to vocalize this in a
way. He's like one size does not always
just fit all. Right. And he uses that,
you know, in a way of like, you know,
not everyone with cereble Pauly is the
same. Yeah. Right. We don't all have the
same type, right? Like, so there are
people that have it's not all one
sizefits-all. And I think that's that
way with anybody, anybody's journey,
anyone's passions. We can share the same
passions, but we're not going to have
the same way to we get into it. And I
think the struggle that we have as
tutors and as mentors, especially in
this day and age and my younger students
that I'm noticing with in is, you know,
the our instant gratification culture,
the social media, you know, all I need
is this. All I need is a 100,000 likes
and I'm good, right? I'll be fulfilled.
But talk about, you know, and that's the
flip side, the double-sided coin to that
encouragement, right? We crave it. We
need it. And we will often get it from
wherever we can get it. And I and a lot
of people get it get and that the flip
side of that is the thumbs the the
thumbs ups that we get. Yes. The any of
the thumbs downs or any of the
criticisms that are the internet is
lousy with feels bad can can equally
knock people down a few pegs. And you
know, we're we're all fully aware of the
power the power of social media and with
Spidey. Spidey know Uncle Ben knew it,
right? With great power comes great
responsibility. But and I so I take that
like as silly as that sounds, but I take
that truly to heart whenever I'm working
with actors that are that are wanting to
pursue a passion and I'm always here to
encourage them and and guide them in
whichever way that's going to that that
I see fits for them. Yeah. Yeah. It's I
mean it's it's cool to uh uh as you as
you get older and you get yourself into
more teaching roles, this is true for me
in my own ways as as I'm in teaching
environments,
whether I intentionally want it to be
this way or not, the teachers that
taught me come through my words, you
know. So like the way I encourage people
that I'm teaching on on, you know, job
sites or whatever it is that I'm working
on now, uh I I I cannot de decouple the
fact that my teachers are speaking
through me. So it's just it's just it's
a beautiful thing. Yeah. And I will and
I will quote them often. I will say this
mentor gave me this line that resonates
with me, this phrase that resonates with
me as a as an actor. I have a phrase and
if I had my uh if I could turn my my
webcam is mounted on my monitor here in
my booth and I so I can't turn it. It's
just like this is what you get. Um but
every time I before I step up to the
mic, I have this quote and it's a
Sanford Meisner quote. If you're
familiar with Meisner, Meisner is is one
of the many acting techniques that there
are as a performer. There's different
teachers, different tutilage, you know,
and the Meisner technique is one of
those. And for me, and I say like I
always say this too, it's like for me
is very applicable in this particular
realm of voice over in how it is our job
as a voice actor to express so much
information solely through our voice,
right? That's that's our channel. That's
our mode of delivery of we're we're
expressing thoughts and feelings and
sometimes especially in the case of
animation movement
just with our voice. That's
uh bas in essence what we're what voice
actors are doing. So an audience goes,
"Oh yeah, I get it. I know exactly
what's happening. Even if they can't see
us, they know what's happening." That's
the that's the skill that voice actors
have. and the Meisner technique. There's
this beautiful quote on what acting is.
And I say this with all anybody that's
learning to wanting to get into voice
over or voice acting. I say voice acting
is not about this isn't the quote, but
voice acting is not about your voice.
It's about your acting. It's capital A
lowercase V because you are in fact
acting with your voice. Right? That's
what voice acting is. It's not about
your voice. It's about your acting
through your voice. Does that make
sense? That that's what I set with
people. So I have this quote from
Sanford Meisner about acting and it's
acting is behaving truthfully
under imaginary circumstances.
It's a very simple quote. It's a
beautiful quote talk but we can go deep
with it, right? You can absolutely go
deep but it's a beautiful encapsulation
of what that means. behaving truthfully
under imaginary circumstances, you know,
and some things in in the world of
animation, there's fewer things that
could be more imaginary than like
talking animals and aliens and objects
that have, you know, talking dogs in
Australia that have a family and a
house. You know, Blue is a great
example.
Such an imaginary circumstance, but
there's truth in that. There's truth
like these these characters all these
characters are acting and thinking and
behaving truthfully in a way that we
connect with as humans and that's a fun
fundamental the fundamental root of
acting and it's that way the audience
goes oh yeah I get it I buy it I totally
understand I connect with that it's all
about connection right so I have that
quote so that's a quote that I always
put out and I was like and I look at
that every time I step up to the
microphone that's such a great one every
time that I go it's behaving truthfully
so every time even there's words in
front of my face. It's what I was doing
with a puppet. Like, how do you take a
as a fun example, I don't have a spoon
in here, of course. Why would I have a
spoon in my thing, but I bring out a
spoon. I I know I should have brought a
spoon. Let's pretend I don't even have a
pen. Wait, do I have a pen?
I have a harmonica.
I have a harmonica. Same thing. Same,
right? Who doesn't have a harmonica?
Okay, Jacob, here's a harmonica. I want
you to tell me
what this harmonica is right now. Okay,
here we go.
Oh, it's a it's a mana uh walking
cheerfully. Okay, but let's just let's
just go emotions. Let's just go. Oh,
sorry. Yeah. What what what what is the
harmonica right now? Dancing. Dancing.
How is he feeling? Cheerful. Cheerful.
Happy. Great. Now, what is this
harmonica feeling now?
Sadness. Solemn. Sad. Right. All right.
Now, what is this Vermonica feeling?
Excitement. Excitement. What else could
it be?
Uh, fear. Fear. Excellent. Excellent.
So, you So, this is what I say. You just
told me that a harmonica was happy, a
harmonica was sad or solemn, and a
harmonica was excited or fearful
with no facial expression, no nothing.
No sound harmonica. No sound. Just by
the simplistic movements that I It's
It's easier with a spoon. You can see it
a little bit better than with harmonica.
But in essence, and so I would say say
it was a spoon. I was like, you guys
just told me that a spoon was happy,
that a spoon was sad, that a spoon was
scared,
right? That is the power of
storytelling. It's the power of of
acting. And in the similar way, that's
where we're having to do. You need to
know. Now, here's the thing with a voice
actor. You can't see that I'm scared.
You can't see that I'm solemn. Right.
That connection point is missing. So,
you have to hear it. You got to hear
that I'm scared. You got to hear that
I'm happy. Right. You got to hear that
I'm exhausted. Yeah. Yeah. Right. And
so, that's that's the building blocks of
of that of of how I get people started
with with that whole thing. So, but
again with the quote so that I use that
as a quote. Say Sanford Meiser acting is
behaving truthfully, right? And then it
goes deep. Why is he feeling that way?
depending on why he's scared will inform
the level of scared, right? The level,
you know, same thing with tired, the
same thing with happy. Depending on
what's going on, what he's thinking,
what he's feeling is going to change the
degree of that, right? And it's all this
instant play that we can that we can get
into that if we allow ourselves to find
it and think about it versus just
looking at words and going, "Okay, I'm
saying words in front of my face now.
I'm voice acting." Haha. And that's the
thing that most people discount. I deal
with it with puppetry all the time. The
public at large inherently discounts the
work needed, the skills needed to build
and acquire to do this work really well.
Everyone just thinks it's just talking.
You just get behind a microphone, just
start talking. Dealt with it a lot in co
everybody just like, "Oh, I just got to
plug my mic. I'm home. I got nothing
else to do now." So, I got so many
things like, "How do I get into voice
work? I just got to plug in my
microphone and my laptop and I can start
making millions of dollars." Right.
Easy, isn't it? Yeah. Right. And so, but
I also deal with that with puppetry.
There's this inherent discount that the
public has at large still that like, oh,
it's just puppets. You just put a little
sock on my hand. There we go. I'm pupier
now. Hello, Jacob. So, nice to see you.
Did you know that puppets eat words when
they talk? Riveting story. Do they? Um,
but anyway, so I I it's something that I
point out with people that work with,
they're like, "Oh, yeah. I guess it is a
little bit deeper than that." And then
when people start to do it, they're
like, "Oh, yeah. That's a little bit.
It's not as easy as all that. Um but um
one of my really quick passing from a
mentor quote and then we will move on
and I will stop talking. No, talk all
day. We're here to talk. Um but again
like taking something that a mentor gave
you that really resonates that resonates
with now I did not know Sanford Meiser.
I believe he was long past when I
started doing this. Um don't fact check
me on that. I don't know. But um his
book came out in the 80s. Um,
the great Mick Wingert. Are you familiar
with Mick Wingert? I'm not. I've coached
and worked with Mick Wingert. Mick
Wingert is people probably would know
him. He's like the go-to Jack Black
voice double. He's like does all like he
does like Jack Black ADR. He ended up
taking over the role of Kung Fu Panda
for other series. He did all the Kung Fu
Panda stuff for video games. He's like
he's it's it's scary how much he sounds
like Jackpot. But he does more than just
that. That just something that I think
people would maybe know him from. But he
teaches voice acting. He's a great coach
and a mentor. And he gave me this
phrase. It's one of those things that
just Whoa. It just hits you. And it was
find your irreducible minimum.
And I was like like that's juicy. What's
your irreducible minimum? And I was
like, "Oo." And it's like, "What is it?"
And that's what I had to discover. And
what I discovered is for me, my
irreducible minimum was not puppetry. I
thought it was, but when I looked at it
deeper like that, like reduce it more.
Reduce it to where you can't reduce it
anymore. It's irreducible at this point.
It's the literal minimum. What is the
kernel? What is the seed? And for me,
it's storytelling. Yeah. It's telling
stories. It's bringing stories to life.
And that opened the doors for me.
Discovering my irreducible minimum
brought me out of like only focusing on
puppetry. It then helped me focus on
telling stories and voiceover, telling
stories through audio production, audio
editing, which I also love. I love that
aspect of bringing a story to life
orally,
you know what I mean? sound immersion,
you know, and especially with the as as
the technology was changing and as
audiobooks were becoming a thing, um
podcasts were starting to take off,
people were like getting their content
like very intimately, right, with our
earbuds and our headphones. And so being
able to start to tell tales in that
realm, knowing that this is how they're
taking it in became a really fun,
interesting way to explore storytelling
and sound design. And I was like, "Oh,
yeah. I love that, too." So being able
to have these multiple passions all
shared the same irreducible minimum.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. And that that was just
a a profound quote that one person, Mick
Wing, gave me. Okay. Give me say someone
from any even someone not wanting to
pursue voice acting they're just
interested in this how would we find
each I love this irreducible minimum
what would be your advice for everyone
to seek out and really kind
irreducible minimum that's a question
for everybody's different but that's it
starts from there what is your
irreducible minimum and it's going to
take some time took me some time to
figure it out
like what is it that truly brings you
joy you know on a on a on a like on the
surface kind of you know stereotypical
like you've all heard it they're like
hey how do I become an actor and they're
like don't
you know don't do this to yourself it's
hard you know and any any like actor on
inside the actor studio have you ever
watched any of those inside the actor
studios like with Jame James Lipton it's
kind of like that right and they were
like hi uh Mr. so so so and so Mr.
Pacino. Uh uh I'm I'm studying to be an
actor and I was wondering and you know
I'm using Pacino as an example but
oftentimes they're like yeah don't do
that like yeah you're in the wrong you
know my advice is don't do this is a lot
of these old older actors would say that
you know cuz it is it's tough but
basically I think a a a softer version
of finding your irreducible minimum is
is basically like find what brings you
joy. Like if you can find the a way to
look at that is it's like if you can
find
when approaching say something in the
arts and if you discover like they
basically like if you can find joy some
semblance of joy doing anything else
go do that
right because but if your irreducible
minimum is this like I can't do anything
else then you're where you need to be
and you need to And this is where you
focus your
journey, right? Pick a focus and pick a
lane. And in the realm of voice over,
when I work and coach people that are
just starting because it can be
overwhelming, right? There's so many
different branches of voiceover, of
entertainment, of acting in general.
There's so many different types.
And voice over is not just one thing. We
don't just go, I just do voiceover,
right? Nobody just does voice over.
They're like, what kind? It's like
somebody saying like, I'm a dancer. What
would the next question be? What kind of
dance? What type of dance? What kind of
dance do you do? Right. It's not like
Oh, no. I I'm a dancer.
Yeah. Yeah. What kind of dance? Dancing
with with your feet. Yeah. I move my
body. Yeah. Okay. Where in things,
right? It's not how it works. you're
like, "Oh, uh, you know, uh, you know,
and they dancers, I love using dance as
an analogy for getting into the arts,
the performing arts, if you will.
There's so many different facets, right?
There's so many different branches in
the performing arts tree. I love to like
use the the a tree as a as a visual
analogy of this. And from the trunk of
the performing arts is like that core
connection point, the acting, us
behaving truthfully as human beings. We
all connect in this similar way. We all
know right away when someone's happy,
when someone's sad, you know, just by
looking at somebody's face, right?
Instant connections can happen, right?
And then thus stories stem from this,
right? It's why we connect to certain
things. It's why you know we people you
know a connection can be created you
know when people go to horror movies
horror movie fans why are they there
connection is to be scared to the jump
scares or whatever right and if they go
to see a horror movie and they're not
scared
they're not connected they're moved out
same thing you go to a comedy show you
want to laugh and if you're not laughing
there's a disconnect there right and so
the that whole there's there's
similarity that we all stem from it's
all it all turns into storytelling. But
I use um in regards to analogizing dance
to voice over. I was like nobody let's
talk about ballet. Have you ever been to
a ballet, Jacob?
Gorgeous. Talk about storytelling. Just
in music and body movement, a full story
is told. No dialogue, no vocals.
solely to told in body language,
brilliant, effortless, gliding, floating
movement and music, right? And we all if
we're everyone any there is not a single
person sitting in the audience of a
ballet performance going, I can do that.
Not a single one. Why is nobody going,
"Oh, I can do that." Look at how easy.
Look at how easy that is. They make it
look effortless. They're floating.
They're gliding. Look at how easy that
is. I can do that. Not a single person
is doing that. Why? Why is no one
watching a ballet performance going,
"Oh, I can do that."
Why? Because I think we as humans, we
inherently know our physical
limitations. Oh, right. Yes. The the
people sitting there going that we know,
oh, they spent years Yeah. training and
practicing to get that good. We watch
like, you know, the B ballroom dancers
like Dancing with the Stars, you know,
watching the pros on there and they're
like, "Oh my god, they're amazing." But
we know they worked their entire life to
be that good, right? But when somebody
sees a voice actor doing what they do,
making it look effortless and easy. Mhm.
Everybody's talking into a mic. I can do
that. Oh, I can do that. Right. So,
there's that inherent like discount. We
immediately it's it's it's interesting,
right? But in essence, we're doing the
same thing. It's the same amount of
training, same amount of skill, same
amount of effort, same amount of
storytelling. Sure. Yeah. That's
happening here through a particular
medium. The ballet, the b the ballet
dancers are telling that story through
their whole body. Yeah. Voice actors are
telling that story through their voice
and connecting with you in the same way.
And that's something that they voice
actors when they start to train and
start to work, they go, "Oh, yeah. Yeah,
yeah. Oh, yeah. There's a lot." Yeah.
Yeah. I I get the visualization of uh,
you know, just your typical iceberg of
like what what you see versus the work
that it takes to go in the tip of the
iceberg. Yeah. Absolutely. It and it
really is that, you know, and it also,
man, I was also thinking of um I had uh
one of my ex-girlfriend's grandmothers
would always say, um uh if if if
everybody liked the same thing, we'd all
be dressed as grandma. And uh isn't that
so great? It's not so great. Uh but it
it makes me think of like, man, there's
no there's no I don't think there's an
accident to the thing that you really
like. Like the fact that you were a kid
and you saw some some puppeteers and
then you saw them break that wall of
like, oh, they're showing the actors and
you're like, that's so cool. I mean,
someone might be sitting right next to
you and think that's not that cool.
Whatever. But so, oh my god, Ian made
fun of so much. I have vivid
recollections. I would be listening to
as a kid listen to my Walkman. Oh, did
you have anti-shock? Did you have bass
boost? I had bass boost. Oh, you had
money like that, too. bass boost with my
and that it was like the I had the cool
uh the the earbuds but they were the in-
ear over the head earbuds. Oh yeah, you
know the ones you know the ones I like
the flat twist basically earbuds but it
was still over the head. Anyway on my
Sony Walkman with bass boost um
listening to I used to record I used to
record movies on my tape recorder used
to record like dialogue just record
full-on movies u but also listen to
soundtracks. I was really big into movie
soundtracks, you know, it all it all it
all makes sense, you know, I it just in
listening to
soundtracks,
you know, even before and granted I grew
up and there was home video for sure. I
lot watched a lot of stuff on home
video, Betamax into VHS and then of
course DVDs, but um growing up, you
know, watching a movie then the
soundtrack I could take with me and
relive the movie and listen to that kind
of stuff, right? And so I love
soundtracks and just songs, any songs. I
was a huge Weird Al fan. I still am a
huge Weird Al fan. Weird Al is very much
a found fundamental
uh building block of who Nate is today.
And my sense of humoring you on this. I
love Weird Al. Up to up to a certain I
want to say up until the either the Bad
Hair Day album or the Poodle Hat album.
Everything prior to that I still have
memorized. If you started to play it, I
could probably sing along with it. Um,
that's that's that just lives in me. So,
I had all the Weird Al tapes, all the
Weird Al uh stuff like that. And I have
a vivid memory of and I would practice
lip-sync
on the bus. I was that kid sitting there
with my headphones on listening to Word
Al and lip-syncing to it
and then in the zone. Yeah. and then
soon as like taking it off and then
coming back into reality, hearing the
cacophony
of laughter and point kids are so
brutal. Yeah. And you know what I mean?
And
yeah, I I'll never forget I remember was
like Yeah. And I thankfully was of the
had the fortitude to be like whatever.
Yeah. Yeah. You were having a
conversation with something that they
couldn't hear is the thing. 100%. I was
just immersed in my own zone. And but
then hearing the laugh and then getting,
"Oh, they're making fun of me. They're
laughing at me." And
at a certain point, I got to the point
where I was like, "Whatever." Yeah. You
like what you like. Not a lot of kids
do. And so I do encourage a lot of my
kids that are art artistically inclined
to Don't let anybody yuck your yum, man.
Yeah, it's not about you actually don't
want to be like everybody else as it
turns out. You want to be like you. But
I mean just you brought when you
mentioned that like somebody sitting
next to you like I don't know about
that. Like I have literal vivid memories
of doing that. I used to do that all the
time. I practiced my lips sync on the
bus um as a kid. For sure. Yeah. Well,
that's great though. I mean you you
followed you know you you followed your
bliss. You you leaned into that thing
and you didn't let the other kids on the
bus uh you know. And the other the other
element to that is too and the thing
that I encourage with a lot of my
younger actors and even younger actors
in their youth but also like newer
adults coming into this voice work to
set the stage for them that's like you
have to work for it. And with the
instant gratification we have a lot of
people that a lot and I've seen it where
it's like because it's not as easy as
all that we give up. they they give up
or they quit, right? And so that's
that's something that could have very
easily happened to me. It's like, you
know, it's too overwhelming. I'll never
be able to do this. But letting that
passion p continue to push me, the
passion was the pusher in my pursuit
alliteration. Heck yeah. You know, the
passion was my pusher for my pursuit of
puppetry.
But write that on a shirt and sell it.
Yeah. Try to say that five times fast.
Speaking of which, did so. It's so
funny. I as I see it up here. I do I do
warm-ups. Let's Let's do a fun Let's do
a fun thing. We're talking about
puppetry. Uh or not puppetry, but in
warming up when I have my uh my students
that I was coaching with today this
morning,
it's important to warm up. Do all this
kind of stuff. And when we're doing v
vocal stuff, a really good warm-up is
tongue twisters. So, and I literally
just saw it and it made me think when I
was doing the the the passion was my
pusher of pursuit of puppetry. Uh, I did
a fun tongue twister that I did with my
kids this morning. Do you want to do it?
Oh, wait. I do. Yes. Okay. I need to
start tongue twisters before podcast.
Can you let me share my screen? Yes. Cuz
I'll let you read it. It's easier if you
can read it. Yes. I love this. This so
great. Okay. Uh, you should be good.
Here we go. The tongue twister of the
day is gobbling gargoyles. Gobbled.
Gobling. Goblins.
Gobling. So, say it once slowly and then
I want you to do it three times fast. Do
you want me to go first or do you want
to go first? Uh, you go first. Okay. So,
it's gobbling gargoyless gobbled
gobbling goblins. All right. Here we go.
Gobling gobbling gargoyless gobbled
gobbling goblins. Gobling gargoyless
gobbled gobling goblins. Gobling
gargoyles. Gobbled gobbling goblins.
There it is. Wait. Oh, I hit the button.
Wait, there it is.
Yeah. All right. Now it's up to you.
Okay. Uh, slow first gobling gargoyless
gobbled gobling goblins. Yep. So, you
can see like this is what we're working
on is the ga going. And you can see how
it's a good tongue twister because it
really works all of the elements of
moving your jaw and your lips. Yeah, I
should have done my face yoga today.
Yeah, face yoga. Oh, so important to do
that face yoga. But for funsies. All
right. You ready? Whenever Whenever
you're ready, sir. Gobling gargoyles.
Gobbled goggling goblins. Gobling. We
got some gobling. We got some gobling
goggling goblins. I'm going to
accidentally say a bad word here.
Gobling gargoyless gobbled gobbling
goblins. Gobling gargoyles. Gobbled
gobbling goblins. Gobling gargoyless.
Gobbled gobbling goblins. Woo.
Nailed it.
It's fun though, right? Yeah. Yeah. I I
hope people are listening to this
wherever they're at in their cars in
their apartments just like screaming
about goblin gargoyles. Wait. Yeah. I
was like, "What? You see goblin
gargoyles?" Goblin goblins. It's like
the uh Did you ever see um Twilight
Zone? Yes. The Twilight Zone the series
and then the movie and they had the the
terror at 20,000 ft. Okay. Yeah. Like
the the goblin that's on the wing of the
plane. Yeah. And in the series it was
William Shatner and in the movie it was
John Lithco
freaking out with the goblin on there.
And I always think of though to put me
into my zone I always think so there's
that. I know that version. I know the
Twilight Zone series version with
William Shatner and I know the movie
version with John Liithkco. But what I
always think about is Jim Carrey as Ace
Ventura on the plane doing Jim Carrey as
Ace Ventura doing William Shatner going
like there's something on the wing some
thing. Yeah. Yeah. My my brain populates
more my brain populates more with the
Jim Carrey. He's he's a a great example
of someone who could like stick a a
storyried scene in your head so quickly.
For sure. Yeah. again. And all of that,
that's elements that I, as I've
continued on in my career, like it's all
a part of me and I access all of it. I
access that Weird Alowl sense of humor
and rhythm and pacing. I learned that
like, oh, Weird Al taught me musical
rhythms and stuff like that as well is
where the comedy lies in the music and
in the pacing. And you know, in addition
to just being a brilliant like parody
lyricist, but also Jim Carrey, talk
about Jim Carrey and like Nick Cage are
people that commit And talk about like
making a choice and going for it. Yeah.
And that's an important element of this
too. But that's also an important
element of the pursuit. The pursuit in
general of your passion that's pushing
you, right? Yeah. Commit to it. Yeah.
Make that choice and stick with it.
Yeah. Yeah. There's a reason why you
have that one. You know what I mean?
Like they didn't hand that one to the
person next to you and the house next to
you. Yeah. Exactly. Exactly. And all of
those just, you know, add elements to
the success that I have found in these
certain avenues, especially in
characterizations and comedy and that
kind of stuff. Yeah. Yeah. Okay. So, so
tell me about I want to rewind back a
little bit. These first six months that
you went back here. Uh uh how old were
you when you first went to New York?
These six months where you're like, I'm
going to get booked on a show. I'm going
to give it my all. I saved up a little
bit of money. I'm in New York. I just
graduated college, so I just turned I
wasn't even 21 yet. So, I graduated high
school at 17, so I was 20. And you got a
couple bucks in your pocket in a dream.
And I mean, I mean, what did this look
like? Did it after the six months, did
it look how you thought? Were you
discouraged very quickly? Um uh I will
say for me, I was able to book my first
thing within the first month. Amazing.
Uh not my first puppet thing, the first
show that I did was within the first
month. And then just hitting the
pavement though, like and it was it was
old school back in the day. It was like
you get backstage the paper to find
where auditions were and go go to that
like and and do that kind of stuff. And
then with it was it was Backstage and
Play Bill. Pay Play Bill had had their
own uh uh um
uh what's the word I'm looking for? I
use words for a living. Uh publication
that you could find auditions for as
well. So I just hit the hit it. And then
in addition I got a job. Uh you know you
got to get finding a job. I my journey
was definitely different too cuz I also
talk about making a passion and making a
choice and I made a choice that probably
that if I were to again it's that
classic like if I were to do over
something I probably would not have been
this stubborn
and the stubborn choice that I made
being an a young actor in pursuit of
performing was I am not going to wait
tables
not going to do it And it wasn't for any
reason of like I'm better than that.
It was be all stemming from my job in
high school was working at KFC and it
was the worst job I ever had. So you
knew what you didn't want to do and I
was like I am ne I made this like solemn
vow to myself at 16 that I was like I
will never work in the food service
industry ever again. Ever. And um
in hindsight,
I probably
could have uh had an easier time in New
York than I did. But at the same time, I
don't regret it because it forced me to
hustle.
It forced me to hustle, to get gigs, to
get money. And what it led me to was
finding job, a job to keep the lights on
in between doing gigs in New York. Um,
and I started working at a uh a
rehearsal studio space and I became a
studio manager uh at this rehearsal
studio space. To even to date me even
further, prior to that, I was a store
manager at Blockbuster.
Mhm. So, in it's like a cool thing to
have on your resume now. Kind of. It's
so vintage. Except if you look back to
it, it's like all the jobs that I've had
like prior to doing performance
full-time was uh 1-hour photo center at
Walmart. A 1-hour photo. You don't need
to do that anymore. Uh Blockbuster and
projectionist at a movie theater.
Three jobs that don't really exist
anymore. They're still projectionists
out there. God bless them. And if I if I
I if I had my brothers, I think I could
thread a 35mm projector still in and I
haven't done it in years, but like I did
it so much. Um the multiplex that I
worked at um only had was 16 theaters,
had 15 35mm projectors and uh only one
digital at the time. And by the time I
left, I think they were already starting
they were only down to like three 35 mm.
Now everything's digital of course, but
that was I was back in the day where I
get to like build movies like build get
the film reels and put them together. It
was cool. It was what a cool job. But so
I had had that kind of work and I'd had
and
studio
store manager experience prior to
getting this job as a studio manager in
New York. And that was the job that kept
me afloat throughout all of my
theatrical endeavors. And it worked out
in a great way. not too dissimilar to a
lot of actors that were waiting tables,
right? Getting to audition and stuff
during the day and then working at
night. They were coming away cash in
hand. I was unfortunately like getting
paid like normal like bi-weekly kind of
thing as like at like a job job. Um, so
I wasn't walking away with cash in hand
every night, but I was immersed in this
theatrical world there working in this
rehearsal studio space. and I got to
make so many great connections with a
lot of performers with different
Broadway productions would rehearse
there. Um, work it was it was part of
NYU. Um, and so working with like a lot
of the NYU uh alumni and stuff like that
in the theater program. Um, so it was a
it was a cool thing and I would not have
found that if I had gone the like I'm
just going to wait tables and do gigs.
Yeah. You know what I mean? Yeah. I I
think there's something to be said about
that because I think I'm kind of like
you in that aspect of um uh I I've got
to kind of like be be around it. You
know, I always I I would go through
stages of telling myself minimum I need
I would tell myself, you know what, I
could just do Uber Eats. I could I could
just you know what? If if I get low on
bills, I'll do this. But I don't ever do
it because it's like as I'm driving the
Uber Eats, I can't stop picturing myself
as like less than I want to be, you
know? And so it's it's kind of it could
be um even almost unreasonable,
but sometimes you got to recognize that
if you are the type that needs that.
Well, I I will say in the reverse, if
you are someone who um seriously all
power to you, if you're able to wait
tables, if you're able to, you know,
drive Uber Eats, whatever, I mean, tuck
your shirt in, be be the hardest working
person there, like remember that you're
you're building up all these attributes
and character traits that will lead into
the things you're passionate about when
you're not making doing that job. But um
yeah, I have a lot of actor friends that
that's how they approach that too.
They're like, "Yeah, I'm doing a role.
I'm playing a role." Yeah. And sometimes
they would go in and like I'm doing
That's a great trick. I'm I I create a
whole new personality from one night to
the next as I'm serving tables. And I
did a very similar thing working at
Blockbuster before there was caller ID.
You know, I got it was funny. It was a
fun little story. Got prank called. got
prank called a lot at Blockbuster and it
was at the beginning of like they were
doing soundboards and it was like Arnold
Schwarzenegger prank called me at
Blockbuster and Alpuccino prank called
me at Blockbuster and that gave me the
idea that I was like I'm going to start
playing along and then some days on on
like slow days and bored days I would
answer the phone in different accents
and play different people and different
names as the manager.
Like I would play characters all the
time. Yeah. Even at Blockbuster. I mean,
that's what you should do though. I I I
think it's it's kind of a a hack on
life, right? It was like be the
character who would serve that role
amazingly. Who you know, someone who
It's not about you, but if someone comes
in to Blockbuster to Red Something, they
walk out and they're smirking from ear
to ear at the character you just gave
them. And you feel good and they feel
good. And how much better could you I
mean what a way to really serve a role
right there. Like you're you're giving
them a story as they come in to get
their stories.
Exact stories as they get their stories.
Yeah, man. What a good That's a good
way. That's a t-shirt. That's the
t-shirt. Here's some stories while you
get your stories. Yeah. No, for sure.
Yeah. I always wanted people and and
that's just again another irreducible
minimum of me personal uh person as a
person. Um not what I want to do, but
like who I am is like I just want to
bring joy. Literally my I just want
people to smile and be happy for a
moment, you know? That's always been my
that's always been my goal. Taking it
back to the job that we worked on
together was an award show for high
school kids that work really hard for
this moment. You know, these are kids
that are going through this process of
becoming the future business leaders and
you know, they're getting recognized for
their hard work and all the stuff that
they put in there and they're there to
be celebrated and that's such a great
energy that I naturally always want
people to feel. I want people to feel
great and feel happy and feel
celebrated. And so when I'm live
announcing
fifth place to first place, guess what?
Every single one of them gets equal
juice. They all get the same amount of
juice. They're equally celebrated
regardless of this person won fifth
place versus this person winning first
place prize in this particular event.
They all get the same amount of acol of
energy and and
accolade from my my read of their name.
I never hit anybody more than anybody
else. And that's always been my kind of
stamp that I do when I do the live
awards announcing. Yeah. So I'm thinking
of like a a m magician finding his
magic. And what's cool is when you
approach it that way, each name actually
has its own energy that you can tap into
for that. Oh yeah, sure. Like if you
just if if you just approach it in a way
of remember I I always think about this
with um uh just big live concerts.
something I see, you know, I I'll be in
the realm of, not to throw them all
under the bus, but rap concerts, for
example, sure, is the quickest way that
I find the performer sending it in,
phoning it in, like they're getting just
messed up backstage. They're not really,
they're not tapping into the fact that
when they walk on that stage, there is
hundreds and hundreds of people who they
got a babysitter that night. They've
been excited about this. It's been on
the calendar. They listen to hours and
hours of your music, you know. So
getting yourself to where you remember
how important it is. It's not about you
as the performer in that moment. It's
about like this is an exciting fun
thing. This person worked a lot for or
they've been excited about it. You know,
if you could tap into that, you'll find
that it's just a a wellspring of of
energy to give right back to them. You
know, it really is and it's fulfilling.
You find it being fulfilling. I do. And
I think of it in that same that you just
reminded me of another great quote that
the great Stan Lee of Marvel fame has
and it's
uh any comic is I may be bastardizing it
or we're not bastard but I might not
quoting exactly but it's basically any
comic is someone's first comic book.
So even though he's doing hundreds and
thousands of Spider-Man
comic books, right, continuing a story,
he always approached it was like any one
of these comic books is going to be
somebody's first comic book. That's kind
of cool to think and it it it fits in
that realm of what you were saying,
right? Absolutely. Everybody, you know,
this could be that person's one night
out for the whole year, right? I feel
that I do a lot of work with um um after
leaving New York, I moved to back to
Central Florida in Orlando for family
reasons um just pre uh COVID and um I do
a lot of work with the theme parks down
here and uh different elements, puppetry
elements, voiceover elements, things
like that. Some fun performance motion
capture kind of stuff for entertainment
things in in the park. And the theme
parks, Disney and Universal, uh,
especially, they all have that same kind
of mindset of like it can be very easy,
especially say a performer that's like
does this show and they do the same
thing over and over and over and over
and over and over and over again. It
might even be something that's like we
hit play and it's the same. It's
literally the same thing, right? I
toured with a show for about four years
called John Tertagia's Imagination and
it was a black light puppet show that
took place under the sea, under the
ocean. It was so cool. The lights would
go out and the stage was only
illuminated in black light. So the
puppets were literally flying like on
stage. Such a cool thing. And it was a
kid shows 45 minutes, but it was all
pre-recorded. It was you hit play and it
is the same. Pardon me. Get out of the
way. It is the same
show. It's the It's hit play and it
goes. The recording is the same. Wow.
Every single time. I did over a thousand
of these shows. Jeez. Um but so how does
one not make it the same? Mhm. Every
every audience is going to be different.
every reaction is going to be subtly
different. Even though the the audio and
the dialogue and there was moments that
the characters are lip-syncing and beats
and story stuff, a lot of it with
blacklight stuff is all a safety issue
because the performers were dowsed in
black. Like it had to be very
strategically choreographed for safety
and to match with the the timing of the
playback, right?
But doing that a thousand times,
there was always finding once you lock
into it, then you you can always find
there's something we can change up a
little bit. There's always a moment that
you can change to give it new life, give
it a slightly different energy, fun
little reactions. If your character's
not if my character is not talking but
reacting, I can change up the reaction
that they make to what's just been
played subtly. This still makes sense.
But again, even in that realm, you can
find new ways to add life, to bring more
life, to change the energy up a little
bit. And often times the audience will
help you with that. Mhm. Right. Does
that make sense? So like in that same
way, you're like, "Oh jeez, here we go."
And we all go through it. Absolutely.
Absolutely. We're all human, right? We
all have bad days. We all have, you
know, but if you are able to and it
takes time and it takes practice, I
think for performers to get to that
point to be able to despite whatever
you're feeling that day, whatever bad
day you've had, it's the it's the age
old adage, right? The show must go on.
Yeah. Yeah. Right. The show must go on.
And
in that moment, however long it is that
you're on there and I have found solace
in it, in myself when I've had bad days
or something horrible's happened and I
still need to go do the show,
finding in that little pocket of time,
that little pocket universe that I'm now
in, we can let that real world go away
for a minute and find new fun energies
in this particular moment, even if it's
repetitive.
Right. And just lock locking on to one
little kid with a very distinctive laugh
that just that makes all of us on stage
like cackling. And what was so cool
doing the the the puppet show I was
talking about because it was playback.
We're not miked. We're not live. They
can't hear us at all. The show's really
loud. So we're talking to each other on
stage and like I vividly remember them.
It's a true story of hearing one little
kid in the front row having such a ball
like a degree above everyone else with a
very distinctive almost iconic hilarious
laugh that I I don't even think I could
replicate it. And it just made us all
crack up the whole time. And that is a
show
easily within probably the 800th time
that we have done this. And that show
stands out to me because that moment
just made us so happy hearing this one
kid be his like whatever it was. It was
like this very like just hilarious laugh
that we could hear so loud and proud and
he was just uh and it's moments like
that that go, you know what?
Yeah, it's all right. We're okay. We're
doing something all right. It's like a
like find a way to get out of your head
and into that room, you know, like like
like like the the magic is is in that
room. If you can tap into it, that's
that's beautiful. Okay. Um we are
getting up here in time, my friend.
[Music]
Anyway, uh we are getting up up here in
time. Um I I would love to ask I can
keep going. I could keep going on and
on. We could talk for hours. We'll have
to do it. We'll have to do a part two.
But yes, please ask me questions. Count
me in. you'll have to be in touch on
what new projects to do. Maybe we'll uh
time it around that and talk about the
projects. But um I would like to just
give me um say people are listening
right now or like you know some
someone's listening right now and they
have their teenage kid in in the back
seat or their 10-year-old in the back
seat and they're fascinated by this and
they're like I want to voice acting
sounds cool, puppeteering sounds cool.
Uh this uh recording audiobooks sounds
cool. Whatever it is uh this this is the
guy to to go explore more. So, not only
are they going to be able to click on
your um your IMDb and and profile links
and such below, but uh what what kind of
advice would you have for them? Where
would you send them to begin? Uh what
encouragement would you give them? If
someone's interested in this, where do
they where do they start? Um such great
questions. So, again, I mean to take
even take it back to, you know, pick
pick a focus. If you're like, I'm
interest, again, voiceover is not just
one thing. Uh even puppetry is not just
one thing. to talk about there's
different forms and styles of puppetry.
Pick one. Pick one to start with. Like
most people are like, I want to do hand
and rod. I want to do the Muppet style
stuff. Then there are nowadays I would
say there are so many free resources out
there um to look up. Um, but in regards
to voice over, I think it's really
important to um you can always if they
you can reach me through your links and
stuff like that and and I'm always an
open book to help guide someone to
coach, work with people, work with
professionals, work with um meet with
people that do this for a living. Um,
don't just go to social media and look
at Instagram feeds of people um and and
say, "Oh, I need to get this mic. I need
to get this thing. They're telling me I
need this, this, this, and this, and
this to get before I even do any kind of
voice over." And all of that is patently
false. There is, like I said, there's no
one one way. Everyone there where
there's is a where there's a will, there
is a way. And not everyone's journey is
different. Not everyone I do. So, meet
with someone. meet with someone that
does this. Talk to them and say what and
really choose. Choose what you want to
do. You can't just go, it's not about
taking spaghetti and throwing it against
the wall for this. It's really important
to pick a primary focus first and start
to learn how to navigate that path. And
as you maintain, you may discover this
isn't for me now. I'm going to go over
here. Or you may discover, oh, this is
for me. Oh, and I'm also learning all
this other stuff that'll lead me down
this other path. That's what happened
with me, right? I love puppetry. Oh, it
led me to voiceover. Oh, which led me to
doing animation. Oh, which led me to do
to video games. Oh, which led me to do
uh audiobooks. Oh, which led me to do
all of this kind of stuff, right? And
because I was like, oh, all of this
stuff that I'm doing totally works for
this and I can succeed in this as well.
Are you kidding me? You I didn't
discover that until I went down this
path. So, pick that one path. And
sometimes it takes people a while to go,
well, what do I want to do? Right? And
one, it's okay to not know what you want
to do. Always it's okay to not know. Um,
but give yourself, so give yourself the
time, give yourself the grace, give
yourself the patience to go, hm, I want
to try this. And do your research.
Research it. Don't just look at YouTube
and Tik Toks and and Instagrams. Check
out books. check out, you know, there
are lots of professionals like myself
and many others that I could also guide
you towards that do this line of work
that coach in the genre that you want to
pursue. You know, there are ones that
that train for animation and video
games, myself included. There are ones
that do solely for audiobooks there,
which is an entirely different beast, by
the way, when it comes to voiceover. Let
me tell you, if people want to do
audiobooks, yes, please. I love them.
But it is a very different beast. Um,
and so yeah, do your research. Do your
research. Um, and reach out and and
connect, contact, go to these people's
websites, look at the work that they've
done and reach out to them. And any of
these people that do coaching like
myself or I promise you will go, "Hey,
yeah, absolutely. Let's talk." And you
know in talking with someone like I had
I'm sure Jacob that you've had with
other mentors of yours that you know
help you go oh maybe I should look at
this or I didn't even think about that.
What a great idea. You know and that's
where it's important to really have this
one-on-one an in uh you know to to chat
with someone who does what you want to
do is the best way to do it. Find the
people that do what you want to do and
ask questions.
That's literally the best thing you can
do. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, that's so perfect.
I love that. What a what a perfect
answer. Okay. Um
I would love for you I'm going to put
you on the spot. Are you ready to Okay,
I'm here for it. Spot. Okay. I would
like say that you had
say that you had a say that you had a
megaphone
to to humanity. I don't need one. No
pressure. Everyone can hear me just
fine. Yes. A mega a megaphone to
humanity. And you have to give them I
mean and it could be cheesy. It could be
funny. It could be uh encouraging. What?
Whatever it is, whatever comes to mind.
And I would love for you, this is the
challenge for you on the spot, a
character that would best communicate
such such
a a message. There's no wrong or right.
You got a megaphone. You could tell
everybody a short message that they may
need to hear from a character that could
speak it. Okay. The stage is yours. Take
your time.
Oh, it's just a Oh, I thought it was
like, what are they? Oh, I I was like,
wait, scenario. That was the setup. It's
like it's a megaphone to humanity. Just
everyone's listening. Okay. Um,
all right. You know, it's going to be
Kermit. He's just going to be on there.
I'm going do my Hey everyone, Kermit the
Frog here. Yay.
I want you all to do what you love.
No matter what it is or what it takes,
just do what you love. And haters going
to hate.
Do what you love. There's a quote.
There's a quote. I love that again.
Quotes that resonate, right? The Little
Miss Sunshine. You ever see the movie
Little Miss Sunshine? Yes. Paul Dano
plays this character that doesn't speak
throughout the whole movie. And when he
does finally speak, it becomes pretty
profound, right? He's gone through this
whole movie silently. He's chosen not to
speak. And at the end, he basically
says, "Do what you love and the rest."
So, is Kermit doing a nicer version of
that? Everyone, do what you love. Follow
your dreams. Follow your passions.
Learn. Don't be afraid. I'm keep the
mic. The microphone's still on. I'm
still going. Don't be afraid to fail.
Guess what? Failure is a great teacher.
And it's okay. You're going to fail.
You're not going to be good right away.
It's gonna just keep going. Keep the
great philosopher Dory from Little Nemo.
Just keep swimming. I'm just naming
other people's quotes. Just keep
swimming. I mean, they are good. You
can't deny it. There's a reason that
they're good and there's a reason that
they resonate, but like just keep
swimming is a a beautiful one. I love
that one. And I think in and yeah, just
keep just keep swimming. Keep doing live
your truth. do like don't don't be
afraid of what other people think of you
and don't let don't let people that are
laughing at you if you're lip-syncing on
the bus sway you from following that
path to a career. Yeah. You you may you
may know something or be tapped into
something that they're simply not and
they don't need to know right now. Um
yeah, it actually I I'll give it one of
my own. Something that I was just
talking about the other day that I
always remember um I rode unicycles when
I was in elementary school. Um, nice.
Yeah, strangely enough, I was on
unicycle. Did you juggle? Did you juggle
while doing? I did not. I did not
juggle. I did actually uh uh bunny hop
on mini trampolines while on a sixoot
unicycle, though, which is sounds
insane. I do not I could There's no way
I could do it now, but I did in
elementary school. Does, but I'm here
for it. Yeah, we performed at Sonics and
Trailblazers.
Impressive. Uh, but anyway, so what's
funny is I always remember the thing
that clicked with me when I first
started riding it. I saw it and I saw
other people do it and I thought they
were cool as crap and I was like I want
to do this and I would you push off the
wall and you fall and whatever. When it
clicked for me it was literally when it
feels like you're about to fall just
keep pedaling
and like that was the most profound
light bulb moment. It worked for me and
I
see. Excellent. When you feel like
you're going to fall, just keep just
keep pedaling. Just keep pedaling. Just
keep swimming. Yeah. Yeah. I I love it.
So good, man.
There's plenty of amazing quotes for
everyone to take home. Uh please look
below, read below, click on the links,
check out Nate's work here. Uh please
reach out to him if you have any more
interest in his work or anything we
talked about today. And uh yeah, we'll
have to do a part two and talk about
more like other fun things. Yeah, I you
know what's funny? I had a I I have a
lot of like philosophical uh uh
character questions about like kayfabe
and um um how we interface with the
world. And yeah, we have uh much more
conversation to have, my friend. Part
two, baby. Part two. It's happening.
Cool. All right. Well, everybody, uh,
I'm going to hit end on this record
here. Drink some water. Stretch.
Hydrate. Do your voice. Hydrate. Please
hydrate.
Water. The breath of life. Get a cheap
filter for your fridge and all that. Um,
yeah. So, anyway, we will see you next
episode. Check out the links below.
Goodbye everybody. Love you long time.
[Music]
Knowledge is power.
Reality is
[Music]
Junkyard Love